Guide to the Thomas Cripps papers, 1839-2009 and undated, bulk 1940s-2009 RL.00269
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Still Photographs Series, 1839-1989, 8 boxes
  - Folders Arranged by Film Title, 1904-198 and undated4
    - Home of the Brave, 1949 (Box ST1)
    - Hot From Harlem (stage), Goin' to Town (stage), The Big Broadcast of 1935 (Box ST1)
    - Imitation of Life, 1959 (Box ST1)
    - The Interns, 1962; The New Interns, 1964 (Box ST1)
    - Intruder in the Dust, [1949] (Box ST2)
    - Island in the Sun, 1957 (Box ST2)
    - I Spy, 1965 (Box ST2)
    - It Happened in Springfield, [1945] (Box ST2)
    - Jim Comes to Jo'burg, 1949 (Box ST2)
    - Joanna, 1968, 2 folders (Box ST2)
    - The Joe Louis Story, 1953 (Box ST2)
    - Jungle Drums of America (12-episode serial), 1953 (Box ST2)
    - Key Largo, 1947 (Box ST2)
    - Lilies of the Field, 1963 (Box ST2)
    - Lost Boundaries, [1949] (Box ST2)
    - Lydia Bailey, 1952 (Box ST2)
    - The Magic Garden, undated (Box ST2)
    - The Maltese Falcon, 1941 (Box ST2)
    - Marie Antoinette, [1938] (Box ST2)
    - Mark of the Hawk, 1957 (Box ST2)
    - A Member of the Wedding, [1952] (Box ST2)
    - Moan and Groan [1929] (Box ST2)
    - Moonrise, circa 1948 (Box ST2)
    - Native Son, [1951] (Box ST2)
    - The Negro Soldier, [1944] (Box ST2)
    - Network, 1976 (Box ST2)
    - Nothing But A Man, 1960 (Box ST2)
    - No Way Out, 1950 (Box ST2)
    - Odds Against Tomorrow, 1959 (Box ST2)
    - Our Daily Bread, 1933 (Box ST2)
    - Panther Girl of the Kongo, 1955 (Box ST2)
    - The Pawnbroker, 1965 (Box ST2)
    - Pinky, 1949 (Box ST2)
    - Porgy and Bess, 1959 (Box ST2)
    - Potash and Perlmutter, 1923 (Box ST2)
    - Proud Valley, [1940] (Box ST2)
    - The Quiet One, [1948] (Box ST2)
    - A Raisin in the Sun, 1960 (Box ST2)
    - Real Glory, [1939] (Box ST2)
    - Sergeant Rutledge, [1960] (Box ST2)
    - The Set Up, 1949 (Box ST2)
    - Shaft, 1971-1972 (Box ST3)
    - Shock Corridor, [1963] (Box ST3)
    - Simba, [1955] (Box ST3)
    - Song of Freedom, [1936] (Box ST3)
    - Song of the South, 1944 (Box ST3)
    - So Red the Rose, [1935] (Box ST3)
    - Sounder, 1972 (Box ST3)
    - Sounder/Learning Tree, [1969-1972] (Box ST3)
    - Stars in My Crown, 1950 (Box ST3)
    - St. Louis Blues, 1957 (Box ST3)
    - Stormy Weather, 1943 (Box ST3)
    - Sundown, [1941] (Box ST3)
    - Sweetback, 1970 (Box ST3)
    - Take a Giant Step, 1959 (Box ST3)
    - Thermidor, Gentleman's Agreement, etc., undated (Box ST3)
    - Topsy and Eva, 1928 (Box ST3)
    - Trader Horn, 1929 (Box ST3)
    - To Live In Peace [1947; TV version, 1951] (Box ST3)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin, 1902 (Box ST3)
    - Watermelon Man, 1970 (Box ST3)
    - Way Down South, [1939] (Box ST3)
    - The Well, 1951 (Box ST3)
    - The World, The Flesh, and The Devil, 1958, 2 folders (Box ST3)
    - Young Man with a Horn, 1950 (Box ST3)
    - The Young One (Great Britain title: Island of Shame), 1960 (Box ST3)
    - Youth Will be Served, 1940 (Box ST3)
  - Folders Arranged by Topics, 1839-1989 and undated
    Consists of folders arranged in alphabetical order according to topic. Original titles have been retained.
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: Moulin Rouge, undated (Box ST4)
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: Abes's Irish Rose, 1946 (Box ST4)
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: Jazz Singer, undated (Box ST4)
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: The Golem, 1921 (Box ST4)
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: America, America [1963] (Box ST4)
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: The Last Hurrah [1958] (Box ST4)
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: Humoresque, 1947 (Box ST4)
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: Sherlock Holmes and Nazis?, 1941 (Box ST4)
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: Man They Could Not Hang [1939] (Box ST4)
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: Ride The Pink Horse, 1947 (Box ST4)
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: Ride Vaquero, 1953 (Box ST4)
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: Sweet Rosie O'Grady [1926 or 1943?] (Box ST4)
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: Straedy Company (or Cobble Stones), 1932 (Box ST4)
    - 1930s Deviant Pix: Potash and Perlmutter, 1923 (Box ST4)
    - 1940s Conventional Themes and Roles, 2 folders (Box ST4)
    - 1945-1949 Pre-Message Movie Intimations (Box ST4)
    - 1960s Pre + Blaxploitation Pix, 2 folders (Box ST4)
    - Eddie "Rochester" Anderson, 1940-1945 (Box ST4)
    - Austin, Texas stills, "The Conquering Horde," [1931], 1930s and 1800s (Box ST4)
      Includes photo reproductions of 19th century images of Austin, and images of movie street sets.
    - Black Athletes: Jack Johnson, undated (Box ST4)
    - Black Athletes: Easy Living, 1949 (Box ST4)
    - Black Athletes: This is the Army, 1943 (Box ST4)
    - Black Athletes: Kenny Washington, undated (Box ST4)
    - Black Athletes: None But The Brave, 1965 (Box ST4)
    - Black Athletes: The Fiercest Heart, 1961 (Box ST4)
    - Black Athletes: Satchel Paige on Rutledge Set (Box ST4)
    - Black Performers as Selves, 1930-1965 (Box ST4)
    - Blackface Cycle, Post Sound, 1930 (Box ST4)
    - Blackface Roles and Routines, 1920-1950s and undated (Box ST4)
    - Blaxploitation, 1953-1970 (Box ST4)
    - Blaxploitation Misc., 1967-1981 (Box ST4)
    - Blaxploitation Misc. TV, 1973 and undated (Box ST4)
    - (Pre) Blaxploitation Misc., undated (Box ST4)
    - Blaxploitation Pix, 1960-1972, 2 folders (Box ST4)
    - Blaxploitation-Post, 1977-1989 (Box ST4)
    - Bojangles As Butler, 1935-1936 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Orfeo Negro, 1959 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Tamango, 1959 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Flame in the Streets, 1961 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Pennywhistles Blues [1952] (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Cairo, 1960s (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Sapphire, 1959 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Sea Wyf [Sea Wife, 1957?] (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Dingaka, 1965 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Stanley Baker, undated (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Woman of Straw [1964] (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Men of Two Worlds [1946] (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Calvert and Adams, undated (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Guns at Batasi [1964] (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Young and Willing [1943?] (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Voice of the Hurricane [1964?] (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Sanders, 1935 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Simba, 1955 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Zulu [1964] (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: The Outcast of the Islands [1952] (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Rhodes of Africa, 1938 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Jew Suss, 1935 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Tiger Bay, 1934 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Proud Valley, 1940 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Timbucktoo, 1937 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Men of Two Worlds, 1946 (Box ST4)
    - British Overseas Productions: Guns at Batasi [1964] (Box ST4)
    - Brown, Jim, 1960s-1970s, undated (Box ST4)
    - Dandridge, Dorothy, undated (Box ST4)
    - Documentary Style, 1926-1972 and undated (Box ST4)
    - Ethnix Misc., 1928-1958 and undated (Box ST4)
    - European Ethnic and Immigrant Groups, 1920s-1960s (Box ST4)
    - Exotic Primitives, 1929-1968 (Box ST4)
    - Exotic Primitives, 1929-1968 (Box ST5)
    - Exotic Primitives (Polynesian), 1941-1954 (Box ST5)
    - Stepin Fetchit, 1931 and undated (Box ST5)
    - Foreign, undated (Box ST5)
    - Foreign: Anna's Sin, Respectful Prostitute, John Kutznulter, 1961 and undated (Box ST5)
    - Foreign-British, 1949 and undated (Box ST5)
    - Foreign Non-British Productions, 1920s-1970s (Box ST5)
    - FSA-LC, undated (Box ST5)
    - Harlem Globetrotters, 1953-1954 (Box ST5)
    - Harlem ('scape), undated (Box ST5)
    - Hollywood Views (special collections, UCLA), undated (Box ST5)
    - Indians, 1930s-1959 (Box ST5)
    - Indians I, undated (Box ST5)
    - Indians I: Van Peebles, et al., 1970s (Box ST5)
    - Integrationism, mid-1960s (Box ST5)
    - Jungle Pix, 1930 (Box ST5)
    - Kung Fu Movies, 1973 (Box ST5)
    - Lincoln Porters, 1918-1921 (Box ST5)
    - Lincoln Motion Picture Co., undated (Box ST5)
    - Maids and Feminine Vieux Ficelles, 1920s-1961 (Box ST5)
    - Mantan Moreland, 1940s (Box ST5)
    - Maps, Cartouches, 1971-1976 and undated (Box ST5)
    - Hattie McDaniel, 1939 and undated (Box ST5)
    - Message Movies: Bright Victory (or Lights Out), 1951 (Box ST5)
    - Message Movies: Stars In My Crown, 1950 (Box ST5)
    - Message Movies: Home of the Brave, 1949 (Box ST5)
    - Message Movies: The Intruder [1962] (Box ST5)
    - Message Movies: Lost Boundaries, 1949 (Box ST5)
    - Message Movies: Detective Story, 1951 (Box ST5)
    - Message Movies: Intruder [1962] (Box ST5)
    - Message Movies: Five, 1951 (Box ST5)
    - Messpix, undated (Box ST5)
    - Oscar Micheaux Films: Wages of Sin [1929] (Box ST5)
    - Oscar Micheaux Films: Temptation, 1928 (Box ST5)
    - Oscar Micheaux Films: Chorus Line, Temptation, 1928 (Box ST5)
    - Oscar Micheaux Films: Underworld [1937] (Box ST5)
    - Oscar Micheaux Films: When Men Betray, 1925 (Box ST5)
    - Oscar Micheaux Films: Black King, 1931-1932 (Box ST5)
    - Oscar Micheaux Films: Unknown Title with Charlie Moore and Ethel Moses, 1929 (Box ST5)
    - Oscar Micheaux Films: Easy Street, 1931 (Box ST5)
    - Oscar Micheaux Films: Daughter of the Congo, 1927 (Box ST5)
    - Oscar Micheaux Films: Unknown Title with Pearl McCormick and Rex Ingram, 1920s (Box ST5)
    - Oscar Micheaux Films: Millionaire, 1928 (Box ST5)
    - Oscar Micheaux Films: The Notorious Elinor Lee [1940] (Box ST5)
    - Oscar Micheaux Films: Harlem After Midnight [1934] (Box ST5)
    - Muse, Misc., 1933 and undated (Box ST5)
    - Musicals: Pre-War, 1920s-1930s (Box ST5)
    - Of Orientals, 1917-1961 and undated, 2 folders (Box ST5)
    - Orioles-Ruth, undated (Box ST5)
    - Oxford, Volumes I, Ia (foreign): Vanishing Virginian [1942] (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Four Jacks and a Jill, 1941 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Belle Starr, 1940 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Ziegfeld Follies, 1944-1946 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Oxford: Margie, 1947 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Duel in the Sun, 1946 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Texas, 1940 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Johnny Come Lately, 1947 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Panama Hattie, 1942 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Free For All, 1949 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Dakota, 1946 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: My Brother Talks to Horses, 1947 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: The Music Goes Round [1936?] (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Three Stooges, 1940s (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Heaven Can Wait, 1943 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Major and the Minor, 1942 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: They Won't Believe Me, 1947 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Duffy's Tavern, 1945 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Monsieur Beaucaire, 1946 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Gas House Kids, circa 1950 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Born to Kill, 1946 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: High Barbaree, 1947 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Senator Was Indiscreet, 1947 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Cairo, 1940s (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Secret of Dr. Kildare [1939] (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Ghost Breakers, 1940 (Box ST5)
    - Oxford: Gorgeous Hussy [1936] (Box ST5)
    - Oxford, Volumes Ib-Ic (foreign), 1930s-1940s, 5 folders (Box ST6)
    - Personality, 1940 and undated (Box ST6)
    - Poitier, Sidney, 1954-1971 (Box ST6)
    - Production Crew Shots, 1929-1973 and undated, 2 folders (Box ST6)
    - Publicity One-Shots: Movies A-M, 4 folders (Box ST6)
    - Publicity One-Shots: Movies N-Z, 2 folders (Box ST6)
    - Publicity One-Shots: Performing, 5 folders (Box ST6)
    - Publicity One-Shots: Unknown titles, 2 folders (Box ST6)
    - Racemovies-Micheaux, 1926 and undated (Box ST7)
    - Race Movie Poster Proofs Micheaux plus Lincoln Stills, 1931 and undated (Box ST7)
    - Race Movies-Sound, undated (Box ST7)
    - Race Pix-New 1990s, 1930s-1950s (Box ST7)
    - Race Pix (Reinkens Films), undated (Box ST7)
      Includes two negative slides and letter to Thomas Cripps from Sharon Reinkens.
    - Sammy Davis Jr., 1950s-1960s (Box ST7)
    - Silent, undated (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: A Colored Girl's Love, 1915 (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Daughter of Mine, Goldwyn [1919] (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Peter Pan [1924?] (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Smith Baby's Birthday [also known as Baby's Birthday, 1929] (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Lady Rose's Daughter, 1920 (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Little Old NY, 1923 (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Black Wife (?), 192- (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Smith's Rodeo, undated (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Señor Jim [1936] (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: What's Your Husband Doing? [1920] (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Kentucky Colonel [1920] (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Kentucky Derby [1922?] (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: The Blind Goddess [1948] (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Day of Faith [1923] (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Al's Troubles [1926] (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: His Trust, 1911 (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: The Perfect Clown [1925] (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Seven Chances, 1925 (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Fable of the Galumptious Girl [1915] (Box ST7)
    - Silent Pix: Swim Princess [1928] (Box ST7)
    - Streetscapes, Crowds, Theaters, Termin., 1940s and undated (Box ST7)
    - Thorpe, Jim, undated (Box ST7)
    - Token Integrationism, 1950s, 2 folders (Box ST7)
    - Trainers and racetracks, 1945 and undated (Box ST7)
    - Unidentified films, undated, 5 folders (Box ST7)
    - Unidentified stills, undated (Box ST7)
    - Van Peebles, undated (Box ST7)
    - Vietnam news shots [1960s-1970s?] (Box ST7)
    - Wartime message movies, 1940-1945 (Box ST7)
  - Other Materials Subseries, 1930s-1976 and undated
    Various files found with the still photographs, related to Cripps's research. Also includes a few unidentified negatives. Original titles have been retained.
    - Clippings, media, etc., 1930s-1951 and undated (Box ST8)
    - Graphics - related to race, 1975-1976 (Box ST8)
    - Negatives, undated (Box ST8)
- Subject Files Series, 1928-2009 and undated [CLOSED], 78 boxes
  Assembled and maintained by Cripps in the course of his research, these files typically contain clippings, articles, images, some correspondence, original manuscripts collected by Cripps, and drafts of writings by Cripps. Selected subgroupings are described more fully below. The boxes marked "TV" found throughout are foldered by sub-topic and arranged in alphabetical order; major topics Cripps researched include black broadcasters, television dramas, and individual television shows (such as Roots, Julia, etc.) Original titles have been retained. Arranged in original order as received. Larger record storage cartons are designated as "RS."
  - Nazi Olympics (1936), research (Box SF1-SF15)
    Clippings and photocopies of articles, newspapers, and notes from Cripps's research on the 1936 Berlin Olympics. Subjects covered include the Nazi Party, anti-semitism, racism, Jesse Owens, modernism, German politics and culture, art and architecture, and Olympic themes and history. The culmination of this research appears to be Cripps's unpublished article, The Arts Competition of the Berlin Olympics of 1936. These drafts are available in the Drafts and Proofs series.
  - World War II research (pre-war and post-war years), 1971-1991 and undated (Box SF16-SF 22)
    Predominately undated. Contents consist chiefly of a considerable amount of research on the NAACP split in Los Angeles; a Negro Soldiers Training Manual, post-WWII, with racist content; and large amounts of clippings used in Cripps's research. There little material on films. More than a folder worth of articles on the 1979 television series Holocaust. opics are organized alphabetically.
  - Race films, 1928-2009 and undated (Box SF23-SF27)
    Includes a folder of fan letters to James Lowe (Title character in Uncle Tom's Cabin) from across the globe. Also, a folder of materials sent from Jimmie Smith (Lowe's manager and publicist) pulled from his personal scrapbook. Scrapbook pages include press photographs, newspaper articles, Lowe and Smith's 1928 tax forms, and other memorabilia.
  - Animation, 1940s-1960s (Box SF28)
  - Various research files (Box SF28)
  - World War II (Box SF29)
  - Spike Lee (Box SF30)
  - Sidney Poitier (Box SF30)
  - NAACP in Hollywood (Box SF31)
  - Thermidor, 1945-1950 (Box SF31)
  - Message Pictures (Box SF31)
  - Black culture (Box SF32)
  - Blacklist (Box SF33)
  - World War II (Box SF33)
  - National film society movement (Box SF33)
  - Councils, foundations, etc. (Box SF33)
  - Short articles (Box SF33)
  - Birth of a Nation (Box SF34)
  - Other films (Box SF34)
  - Documentaries (Box SF35)
  - Blaxploitation (films) (Box SF36-SF39)
  - Miscellaneous (Box SF40)
  - Film clippings (Box SF40)
  - African American films (Box SF41)
  - Sidney Poitier (Box SF41)
  - Black culture (Box SF42)
  - Ethnics (Box SF43)
  - Depression (Box SF44)
  - Films (Box SF44)
  - TV, 1967-1980 and undated (Box SF45-SF47)
  - TV (A-Z) (Box SF48-SF51)
  - Visual sources/theory (A-W) (Box SF52-SF55)
  - Visual sources/theory (A-C) (Box SF56-58)
  - African Americans in film (A-C) (Box SF59-SF62)
  - Film history (Box SF62-SF68)
  - "Current Topics" (Box SF69-SF71)
  - Research materials on African American topics (indexes, catalogs, inventories), A-Z (Box SF72)
  - World War II (Box SF73)
  - Nazi Olympics (Box SF73)
  - Film Society movement (Box SF73)
  - African film by Africans (Box SF73)
  - Message Pictures (Box SF74 (RS))
  - Race films (Box SF74 (RS))
  - TV (Box SF74 (RS))
  - Silents (Box SF74 (RS))
  - Blaxploitation-v. Peebles era (Box SF74 (RS))
  - Film Society Era (Box SF75 (RS))
  - Newspaper clippings (Box SF75 (RS))
  - Film stills (Box SF75 (RS))
  - World War II (Box SF75 (RS))
  - Black culture (Box SF75 (RS))
  - Hollywood (Box SF75 (RS))
  - Current politics (Box SF75 (RS))
  - TV (Box SF76 (RS))
  - Silent film (Box SF77 (RS))
  - Depression Era (Box SF77 (RS))
  - Postwar Era (Box SF77 (RS))
  - Some correspondence (Box SF77 (RS))
  - Cassette tapes (Box SF77 (RS))
  - Slides (Box SF77 (RS))
  - Blacks in early sound (Box SF78 (RS))
  - Crossover (items on films, e.g. Sounder) (Box SF78 (RS))
  - Richard Grupenbott - oral history race pix (Box SF78 (RS))
  - Still pictures (Box SF78 (RS))
  - Black culture (Box SF78 (RS))
  - World War II (Box SF78 (RS))
  - Sidney Poitier (Box SF78 (RS))
  - Film Society (Box SF78 (RS))
  - Paul Robeson TV Project (Box SF78 (RS))
  - University Publications of America (Box SF78 (RS))
  - Unprocessed 2017 addition, 10 boxes (Box SF79-SF88)
- Writings Series, 1979 and undated [CLOSED], 29 boxes
  Contains drafts, proofs, and supporting files for Cripps's many writing projects and publications, centering around his research on representations of African American in American popular culture, especially his two-volume work on film, Slow Fade to Black and Making Movies Black, 1993. Some materials relate to The Green Pastures, a guide to the black folk film classic (1936) of the same name, edited by Cripps and Tino Balio and published in 1979. Other writings represented in the files include the essay The Negro Soldier (1944): Film Propaganda in Black and White written with David Culbert; and the book Hollywood's High Noon, regarding the formation of Hollywood in the years before television. Original folder titles have been retained; arranged in original order as received. Larger record storage cartons are marked as "RS."
  - Making Movies Black (Box W1-W8)
  - Slow Fade to Black (Box W9-W13)
  - Making Movies Black and Hollywood High Noon, photographs (Box W14)
  - Miscellaneous writing drafts (Box W14)
  - Hollywood High Noon (Box W15-W16)
  - Miscellaneous (Box W17)
  - The Arts Competition of the Berlin Olympics of 1936, drafts (Box W18)
  - Miscellaneous (Box W18)
  - Miscellaneous (Box W19)
  - Negro Soldier and Green Pastures, 1979 and undated (Box W20-W22)
  - Speeches (Box W23)
  - Hollywood High Noon (Box W24-W27)
  - Hollywood High Noon (Box W28 (RS))
  - Miscellaneous short papers (Box W28 (RS))
  - Copyright/fair use materials (Box W28 (RS))
  - Miscellaneous writings and rewrites (Box W29 (RS))